<!--Bereit für Copy&Paste
    
Links wurden so weit es geht manuell mit Suchen&Ersetzen angepasst / muss aber trotzdem noch manuell überarbeitet werden ([kontakt] - Shortcodes)
    
Kein valides XML-Dokument!!!-->

[accordion-item title="DLR-Nachwuchsforschergruppe am DFD (GARS O'Higgins), Reprocessing ERS-1/2 Archive of GARS for glaciological products along the AP "]The working group of Matthias Braun contributes to the HGF Nachwuchsforschergruppe of Dr. Kathrin Höppner at DLR DFD by supervising a MSc and PhD student. The aim of the PhD project is to derive quantitative glaciological variables from large-scale processing of the entire ERS-1/2 archive over the Antarctic Peninsula stored at DLR. The ERS archive was acquired between 1991 and 2011 during various acquisition campaigns at the German Antarctic Receiving Station (GARS) near the Chilean base O'Higgins. The working group at FAU provides its knwoeldge and expertise on SAR processing as well as algorithms where required.[/accordion-item]
[accordion-item title="CaTReS - Canopy traits in remote sensing of floristic and functional vegetation patterns, DFG-Normalverfahren FE 1331/2-1 "]<h4 style="margin-bottom: 0in;">DFG FE 1331/2-1</h4>
[caption id="attachment_3887" align="alignright" width="135"]<a href="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/CaTReS.png"><img class="wp-image-3887 size-medium" src="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/CaTReS-135x300.png" alt="CaTReS" width="135" height="300" /></a> AISA Dual data of the CaTReS study site (RGB - 734, 641, 549 nm)[/caption]
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: left;">Funding period: 2013-2014</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: left;">Project team: <a href="http://www.geographie.nat.uni-erlangen.de/?p=3499">Hannes Feilhauer</a></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: justify;">Maps of vegetation patterns such as spatial variation in floristic composition, plant traits and plant functional types are required in ecology, ecosystem modelling and nature conservation. One frequently applied approach to generate these maps relies on imaging spectroscopy. In this approach, statistical relationships between a vegetation sample and the corresponding canopy reflectance are quantified and subsequently applied onto the imagery. Although several successful examples of such applications exist, fundamental questions regarding the causal relations between vegetation patterns and canopy reflectance are still open. In particular the role of canopy optical traits remains poorly understood. Canopy optical traits determine the reflectance signal of vegetation and include canopy biochemistry, morphological and structural properties. CaTReS aims to test the qualitative and quantitative contribution of these traits to remote sensing of vegetation patterns in a test site in Southern Bavaria.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: left;"><a href="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/dfg_logo.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-3808" src="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/dfg_logo-300x101.png" alt="dfg_logo" width="130" height="44" /></a></p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in; text-align: left;"></p>[/accordion-item]
[accordion-item title="DIARS - Detection of invasive plant species and assessment of their impact on ecosystem properties through remote sensing"]<h4 style="margin-bottom: 0in">EU BiodivERsA, DFG FE 1331/3-1</h4>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: left">Funding period: 2014-2017</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: left">Project team: <a href="http://www.geographie.nat.uni-erlangen.de/?p=3499">Hannes Feilhauer</a>, <a title="Sandra Skowronek" href="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/personen/sandra-skowronek/">Sandra Skowronek</a></p>


[caption id="attachment_3797" align="alignright" width="300"]<img class="wp-image-3797 size-medium" src="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/DIARS_CI-300x300.jpg" alt="DIARS_CI" width="300" height="300" /> Invasive moss species<em> Campylopus introflexus</em> in the dunes of Sylt, Germany[/caption]
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: justify">Biodiversity conservation includes the development of warning and rapid response systems for biological invasions and urges investigations of their impacts on ecosystem function and services. In this context, the systematic, objective, and synoptic view on Earth of remote sensing systems offers a great opportunity to target biological invasion and their impact across various spatial and temporal scales. Within DIARS we aim to</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: justify">1. characterize the ecosystem impact of invasive plant species through the combined use of field and remotely sensed data.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: justify">2. support monitoring, prediction of spread and risk assessment of invasive plant species as preconditions for management measures and mitigation.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in;text-align: justify">For this purpose, we analyse and map the local distribution of the invasive species<em> Campylopus introflexus, Prunus serotina</em> and <em>Oxalis pes-caprae</em> and their impact on ecosystems in Germany and France.</p>
&nbsp;

Project website: <a href="http://diars.vgt.vito.be/content/home">DIARS</a>

&nbsp;

Project partners:
<ul>
	<li>Carnegie Department of Global Ecology, Stanford, CA, USA</li>
	<li>Fondazione Edmund Mach, San Michele all'Adige, Italy</li>
	<li>KIT, Karlsruhe, Germany</li>
	<li>KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium</li>
	<li>U de Picardie Jules Vernes, Amiens, France</li>
	<li>Vito, Mol, Belgium</li>
</ul>
<p style="margin-bottom: 0in"><a href="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/Biodiversa_Light-version_LOGO.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-3808" src="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/dfg_logo-300x101.png" alt="dfg_logo" width="151" height="51" /><img class="alignleft wp-image-3807" src="https://geographie.cms.rrze.uni-erlangen.de/files/2018/02/Biodiversa_Light-version_LOGO-300x86.jpg" alt="Biodiversa_Light version_LOGO" width="213" height="61" /></a></p>[/accordion-item]
